Somebody help me! I can't swim!
Get the raft!
Somebody help me!
What is that?
It's a glow stick.
How does it work?
From some kind of chemical.
Do you think anybody else is here, sir?
It's just an island.
There's nothing here.
- I'm thirsty.
- Yeah, me too. I'm hungry.
What if there's no water?
We're all thirsty and we're all hungry.
We should just try and get some sleep.
And tomorrow we'll figure out
what we're gonna do.
Water.
Sir. Sir.
I found water.
Well, that's it, Colonel.
What's that?
It's a conch.
My granny had one.
If it had a hole in it right there
you could really blow it, like a trumpet.
Come on! Give us some.
Come on.
Okay, listen up. Whoever holds the conch
gets to speak. That's the rule.
Is this like assembly, sir?
Yeah. Except anybody
who wants to speak gets to.
But not before they get the conch.
Right. There doesn't seem
to be anybody here except us.
- And a pig.
- It was a wild boar.
No, it was a regular pig.
Big, but regular.
A regular pig must have
got here from people.
Yeah. If there's pigs, there's people.
Okay, cadets. Like I said,
this island's probably uninhabited.
- We don't know. We've gotta explore.
- There's a lot to do.
But the main thing is, we're not
by ourselves. We got Captain Benson.
Can I speak?
The most important thing is,
who knows we're here?
Nobody knows we're here.
They know where we were going.
But they don't know where we are.
We never got where we were going.
- Where were we going?
- We were going home.
I'm sure they're looking.
We should set up some kind
of steady signal, like a fire,
and keep it going all the time.
And we're gonna have to have rules.
Can I have the conch?
Yes, Ralph's right.
We've definitely gotta make a fire.
- Sir, are you the leader?
- Jack's the oldest.
- But Ralph's the colonel.
- I think it should be Ralph.
- I vote for Ralph.
- Yeah, he's a colonel.
- Yeah, Ralph.
- He's the colonel. Ralph.
- I guess you just won the election.
- It doesn't matter who's in charge.
We've just gotta work together.
First, we build a camp.
Be careful.
There's probably a lot of berries and
things that look okay but are really poison.
I know what's poisonous or not.
My brother did Outward Bound,
learned how to survive. He taught me.
Did he do Outward Bound in the tropics?
- Not exactly.
- Then where?
Colorado.
There are totally different poison plants
in Colorado than in this place.
So we've gotta take precautions
or it won't matter.
- What won't matter?
- Whether we get rescued.
Better learn to live with yourself,
because we ain't gonna get rescued.
- What are you talking about?
- Just being logical.
A plane goes down in the ocean, there's
no wreckage - who's gonna find us?
- Why don't you just shut up?
- Are you telling me to shut up?
What we need around here is positive
people, not people trying to scare people.
What we don't need is you, shitbrain.
His name's not shitbrain. It's Piggy.
Yeah, Piggy! Yeah!
Shut up. Everybody just shut up.
- It's just cos you're new.
- No, it's not. It's always this way.
Just cut it out, okay?
- Mama, mama, can't you see
- What the army's done to me?
- They put me in a barber's chair.
- Spun me round, I had no hair.
- I used to drive a Cadillac.
- Now I'm marching in a pack.
- I used to drive a Chevrolet.
- Now I'm marching for my pay.
- They took away my TV.
- Got me doing IOT.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Whoa, oh, oh.
- Come on, let me try.
- I got it, I got it.
Shit!
- Damn! Mother...
- Swearing won't help.
- Listen, Piggy, shut your fat ass.
- Hold it! Hold it!
Hey, wait a minute.
Piggy, give me your glasses.
- Hey, give 'em back.
- Trust me.
What are you doing?
- Fire!
- Yeah!
Jesus, it's spreading!
Put it out. Stomp on it.
Come on, run and stomp on it.
Beat it back. Use your jacket.
Beat it back.
Come on, guys, beat it back.
About time you showed up. People ought
to be fined for being late for fire watch.
Bullshit.
The forest was totally dark,
but he had to keep going
because the thing was behind him.
The pus was everywhere.
He could feel it and, all the while,
the thing behind him kept coming closer.
And then, suddenly,
he realised it wasn't any normal plants
or bushes he was trying to run through.
It wasn't the leaves or plants
brushing up against him,
touching his arms and face.
It was thousands of claws,
long claws, grasping at him,
trying to stop him
and hold him for the thing.
And he tried to get away, but they held on,
choking him. He tried to scream.
It's only a story.
It's not real.
I don't know if he can hold up.
What if he suddenly gets really sick?
Man, you gotta stop worrying
so much. We got it made.
No parents, no teachers,
no academy, no girls.
Of course,
I wouldn't mind getting a little.
- Like you ever got any.
- Well, I still wouldn't mind.
Oh! My arm.
You okay?
Psych!
Nearly got him. Next time.
Do you think it has any protein in it?
Here, give it here.
I heard they're supposed
to taste like chicken.
Want some?
- Are you telling the truth?
- Yeah.
- We don't believe you.
- Yeah, you're lying.
Why aren't you getting ready?
Sir, is it really true?
You bet it is. Simon's right.
We're gonna be rescued.
Get your things together, guys.
We're going home.
I...
Beat it, you kids.
Come on. Why isn't anybody
getting food or wood?
- Spit! Come on!
- Come on! Spit!
- Spit!
- Go on, spit!
- Spit.
- I got it. There it is.
No, you're not gonna get out
until I see it splash in the ocean.
- That made it.
- No, I didn't see it splash.
- Ow!
- See? It splashed again.
Ha! It's our turn to have fun.
Assembly!
What's going on?
The reason I'm calling this assembly is,
too many people are screwing around and
not working. There's a bunch of things.
Some kids don't know
when to use the bathroom.
There was this one kid the other day,
he took a shit in his pants
and then sat in it.
I'm not naming names cos it's possible
Mikey couldn't help it.
Was it green? Was it running
down your legs?
Everybody shut their goddamn mouths!
Ralph's got the conch.
All I mean is, we have
to have more discipline.
And more spearfishing.
We've gotta have real food.
- We should be hunting pigs.
- That's all I got to say.
- Anyone else want the conch?
- Some jerk-off stole my pocketknife.
Yeah, things are disappearing all over.
- What are we gonna do with thieves?
- Kick the shit out of them.
- Shove their dick in the conch!
- Put a stick up their butt.
- Ram it in there!
- Okay, okay!
We can't have kids
stealing and running wild.
We're gonna have to have stricter rules.
And hand out demerits, I guess.
- Demerits!
- Demerits?
Demerits for grand larceny?
- Eat shit and die.
- Yeah!
Sir?
Are we ever going home?
Of course we are,
as soon as they see our signal.
Jack says that we're never
gonna be rescued.
No, you misunderstood him.
That's not what he meant.
That's exactly what I meant.
There's eight million islands out here.
Why should they find this one?
Don't listen to him.
We will be rescued, Peter.
Honest.
Are you going hunting for pigs again?
I wanna come next time.
Me too.
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
Hey, cut it out.
Are you crazy? Stop it.
You know why Jack got sent
to military school?
- Because he was in trouble.
- Who says?
Tony. Jack told him he took a car
and drove it on the highway.
- He's a liar. He didn't steal a car.
- He didn't say he stole it.
He borrowed it. It was a neighbour's.
And the neighbour was away and he just
borrowed it and drove it on the highway.
He probably rode his dad's bicycle
around the block.
- Then how come he got arrested?
- Yeah, by the highway patrol.
They got him doing 80.
What time is it?
What difference does it make?
Well, if I knew what time it was
I'd know what's on TV.
- I'm not even sure what day it is.
- It's Monday.
- Are you sure?
- I'm sure.
Mondays. Monday's ALF.
ALF comes on at eight o'clock.
It's a lot later than eight.
Yeah. But I bet we're in
a different time zone.
I bet it's really about eight o'clock and
ALF's causing some trouble right now.
Yeah.
They're mean and they move fast.
They ain't gonna be easy to kill.
You gotta get 'em first time,
in the heart.
I guess the spear's gotta be real sharp.
We have to have a strategy.
You know, trick 'em.
Oh, sure. How we supposed to do that?
You just smoke 'em out.
You crawl up, light a little fire.
We have to practise on stuff that moves.
Ew.
Jesus Christ.
When do we do it?
I mean, like, what time of day?
You always go right before dawn.
Maybe you can catch 'em asleep.
Simon!
Simon can't stay with him
every single second.
Sh.
And he's scared of everyone else.
I'm scared of him. He's crazy.
We've gotta do something.
- Maybe we should tie him down.
- That or get rid of him.
Come on. He's hurt bad and he has
a fever. We've gotta take care of him.
Why bother? He ain't gonna make it.
- We've gotta take care of ourselves.
- Exactly.
Captain Benson!
Captain!
Save your breath, man.
He's gotta be close by.
He's probably just lost.
Look.
It's nobody's fault, Simon.
He just didn't know what he was doing.
I don't think it's what you think.
I don't think he's dead.
- Why not?
- Where are his shoes?
We've gotta keep looking.
He just swam out in 'em.
And his belt? He left his pants
and swam out in his shoes and belt?
He was crazy, Simon.
- There it is! Get it!
- Get it!
- Kill it!
- Yeah!
Roger, are you okay, man?
That was some jump.
I got him right up his ass.
- Right up the ass!
- Yeah!
- Get him! Get him!
Hey, come on! Cut it out! Stop it!
- You dorks. It hurt.
- I know it hurt.
I've been thinking about a clock.
We could make a clock.
Yeah, sure, Piggy. Then a TV.
No, really. We could make a sundial
with a stick in the ground.
What's that noise?
- Look, there it is!
- Help!
Over here!
- Please!
If you guys hadn't let the fire go out
they would have seen it.
- Hey, man, we were hunting.
- Great. Killed a pig.
Face it, you fucked up.
We could have been rescued.
Back off, man.
I'm sick of your shit and so's my gang.
Your gang? What's that supposed to mean?
It means that if you know what's good for
you you'll stop trying to run everything.
Stop it!
I'm sick of this. I'm gonna make a camp
for hunters and guys who wanna have fun.
Yeah!
Come on, that's crazy.
We've gotta work together.
- Come on, what do you say?
- I say fuck you.
And that goes for you too, Miss Piggy.
Come on, let's get out
of this kindergarten.
- I'm with you, Jack.
- Right on, Larry.
When you other brats get older or get
hungry enough, you can come join us too.
They're back! Simon, they're back!
Are you all right? It's only a storm.
- Where's your brother?
- I don't know.
He must be in the other shelter.
Quick, get out of there!
That tree's gonna go!
Help me!
Over here!
Help!
Where are the others?
I don't know.
Peter, where are you?
Ralph!
Yeah?
Where are you?
Over here.
Wait. Wait for me.
Well, come on.
- Where'd you get that from?
- Right here.
Ralph!
- Yeah?
- Over here. We found fruit.
Do you think the other guys are okay?
- Who cares?
- Okay, dork. I was just asking.
We should relight the fire.
- Gross.
- Where are they?
If they didn't get blown away
they're probably hunting.
What good will that do? They can't cook
pigs without a fire. They'll get trichinosis.
- What's that?
- It's bugs that live in pigs.
We knew that.
What's this shit about a monster?
We'll send you back to kindergarten.
- I'm serious.
- Okay, what kind of monster?
Did it have fur and poisoned fangs,
or long, slimy tentacles?
It growled and it came out at me.
And its mouth, it was wet.
- Maybe it was a bear.
- Sounds more like a reptile.
Sounds more like bullshit.
- We heard it all right.
- Yeah.
Whatever it is, it's in there.
You should have seen it.
He was scared shitless.
Do you think there was something there?
Some kind of wild animal or something?
- I know it. We heard it growl.
- Is it close?
Just over the big rise
behind our camp. Real close.
Holy shit.
- I just thought you ought to know.
- Yeah.
Thanks for the fire.
Here come the reserves.
- Better keep on your toes tonight.
- What do you mean?
- You'll find out.
- What are you doing with that?
Next time we kill a pig,
we're gonna have a barbecue.
- You mean no one's on fire watch?
- Why can't we have the fire down here?
If we want anybody to see the smoke
it's gotta be up there.
Nobody wants to be
up there alone any more.
There's something loose
on this island - a monster.
- There's no monster.
- There's something.
- So what do you want?
- Jack wants the survival knife.
It's not his. It belongs to the camp.
Yeah? Well, there's a new camp now,
and he wants it.
Yeah, and Tony wants his shoes,
socks and his junk.
Take Tony's stuff
but you can't have the knife.
- He's a defector. Another damn defector.
- It's because of the monster.
I told you there's no monster.
Tony knows there's no monster.
Tony just wants to be a hunter
and he's too chickenshit to get his stuff.
But what if there is
some kind of big animal?
Yeah.
Oh, great. Two more traitors.
Sorry, Ralph.
Good riddance.
Sh.
Go on! Get the knife! Get the knife!
Bring that back! You have no right!
Get back here! What the hell
do you think you're doing?
Oh, God!
They broke my glasses.
Anyone who wants to come up has to ask.
- Where are the others?
- They're hunting.
Where's that cave you found?
- Don't you know?
- Yeah, but I'm not going back.
- I already showed Jack and the others.
- Tell me where it is.
You shouldn't go there.
I just want to look.
I've got a glow stick.
It's over there in the forest.
Put it here.
Sharpen a stick at both ends.
This is a present for the monster.
Okay, Rambo, you've made your point.
What do you want?
We killed a pig today.
There's going to be a feast.
You can all come eat
with us if you want to.
- Go on. Now.
- The chief has spoken.
See you tonight, girls.
Count. Cadence delay. Cadence count.
- Whoa, one.
- Airborne rangers!
- Two.
- Better do your best!
- Three.
- Or you'll find yourself...
- Four.
- In front leaving rest.
- One.
- Hit it.
- Two.
- Three.
- Hit it.
- Four.
One, two, three, four.
We like it here. We love it here.
We finally found a home.
- A what?
- A home.
- A home away from home. Huh!
Luke, take them some meat.
I promised I'd get meat.
Didn't I, Ralph?
I want you to tell the little ones that
I made you a promise and I kept it. Say it!
You kept your promise
but not the fire watch.
You think one meal is worth not getting
rescued? We've gotta be one group again.
I agree. You can join my camp
and have all the meat you want.
We don't want your meat.
Oh, yeah. Then why'd you come?
We came to try
and talk some sense to you.
You don't have the conch.
The conch is in our camp,
where it belongs.
What's the matter, tits?
Were you afraid to bring it with you?
- The conch doesn't count any more.
- Stop that!
Nobody's interested in you
and your conch.
Take your fat friend and shove off.
You've had all the meat you can eat.
Come on, hunters!
Roger's the pig!
Come on, hunters! Billy's the monster!
The monster!
It's the real monster! Kill him!
What are we gonna do?
Piggy, that was Simon.
What good are you doing
talking about it? It was dark.
- We were scared.
- I wasn't scared.
You were scared.
Anything could have happened.
It wasn't our fault.
It was. We were there
and we didn't do anything about it.
There was nothing we could do.
There was too many of them.
- That's not the point.
- It was an accident.
That's what it was...
a terrible accident.
- Hi.
We came here to see
if you guys have any fire.
Ours is out.
- Everything's out.
- On account of the storm.
We gotta get back.
Hold on a minute.
I wanna talk to you about last night.
Ralph.
We left early.
We were real tired.
- It isn't fair.
- I never touched it.
- He didn't.
- Butt out, or you'll get it.
From now on, any more criminals
are gonna be put on that island to starve.
- Give it to him. Whip him.
- Now you're gonna get it.
Yeah!
Stop it!
I'll get fire, I promise you.
Tomorrow we'll hunt again.
But we have to be careful
cos the monster might come any time.
But didn't we... I thought we...
No. It could come again any time,
in any shape.
Just when we're not ready,
it could be there.
Maybe we should just build
a raft and row off.
I will if you will.
- Well?
- We don't really know what's out there.
I bet you out past the reef
lots of boats come by every day,
and one of them could rescue us.
Yeah? Well, suppose it didn't.
Suppose it was Russian.
Then what? We'd be taken prisoner.
The Russians wouldn't take us prisoner.
I don't know. Major Dingledine,
my new dad, told me...
Major Dingledine?
Yeah. He said that if
the Russians invaded the US,
they would take the kids
and separate us from our parents -
and I know it sounds weird -
but they might make us go into
the Olympics or something like that.
- I don't see what's so funny.
- Piggy,
I don't think you have to worry about the
Russians forcing you into the Olympics.
Hey, what's that?
Where do you think it comes from?
A Russian submarine,
full of Olympic athletes.
Ralph, wake up.
- What is it?
- Sh. Just listen.
There's someone out there.
- I don't hear anything.
- Sh. Listen.
I hear you there, Piggy.
Come outside, Piggy. I want you, Piggy.
Ha, Piggy!
Come on out, Piggy.
Why can't you just leave us alone?
- Give 'em back!
- I got the glasses!
Here.
We did everything just the way
grown-ups would have.
Why didn't it work?
Things'd be much better, Ralph,
if it wasn't for him.
I wish he was dead.
- No, you don't.
- I do.
We could just give up
and join his tribe.
Then we'd at least be with the others.
No, Piggy.
Ralph, I can't see.
I know.
Halt! Who goes there?
Don't be stupid. You know who we are.
We brought the conch.
I'm calling an assembly.
- Where's Jack?
- What do you want now?
You heard. We brought the conch.
I'm calling an assembly.
Why don't you two fuck off? This is my
end and my tribe. Keep to your own end.
You won't keep to your end, tearing up
our camp and stealing Piggy's glasses.
- You've gotta give 'em back.
- Got to? Who says?
I do.
Piggy can't see. If you wanted to have
a fire all you had to do was ask.
- I don't have to ask!
- Come on! Yeah! Yeah!
- I've got the conch. Let me speak.
- Get outta here, Piggy.
Stop that, Roger. Let Piggy speak.
Please. This is serious.
Get out, fat ass. Get away.
Go back to your own camp.
What I wanna say is,
if we don't get rescued
we might have to live here for a long time.
Maybe the rest of our lives.
If we are stuck here until we get old
then we can't go on acting like kids.
We've gotta be sensible
and make things work.
No!
You're not gonna get away with this.
Yeah? And what are you gonna do? Huh?
What are you gonna do about it?
You're out of it, pal.
You're on your own.
About time.
- You guys by yourselves?
- Yep.
- Listen, you two, you have to stay awake.
- Give us a break.
What do you think? You have to be 11
or you can't stand a watch?
Just stay awake.
What's the big deal?
There's nobody left except Ralph.
They're scared of the monster.
You said we didn't believe
in the monster. You said.
I'm pretty sure we don't.
Sam! Eric!
It's me.
You shouldn't be around here, Ralph.
You're not allowed. The hunters
are gonna come after you.
Yeah. And Jack had Roger
sharpen his stick at both ends.
If that happens, it'll be
because you let it happen.
If you don't stand up to him
you're just another one of his slaves.
Hey, keep alert down there!
Light another one.
We gotta smoke him out.
He's over here!
See anything over there?
No.
Nothing.
Jack!
Get him!
What are you guys doing?
Visiontext Subtitles:. Abigail Smith
ENHOH